netcraft.com 2012-12-02

# Privacy Statement | Netcraft

**Fair Use:** Please note that use of the Netcraft Blog is subject to our Fair Use and Copyright policies. For more information, please visit http://news.netcraft.com/fair-use-copyright, or email info@netcraft.com. 

Netcraft has created this privacy statement covering its web sites in order to demonstrate our commitment to privacy. This Privacy Policy explains the information gathering and dissemination practices for our Web sites in the netcraft.com, netcraft.co.uk, and netcraft.net domains, and for people using the Netcraft Toolbar and how this information is used. If you have any queries or requests concerning your personal information, please contact us at [webmaster@netcraft.com](mailto:webmaster@netcraft.com). 

  * **Information Automatically Logged**

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web site. Your IP address may also used to display regional advertising banners. 

  * **Advertisers**

Sometimes advertisers may use third party banner servers to display banners on our site. These servers are not under Netcraft's control. 

  * **Cookies**

Netcraft uses cookies in areas of the site requiring authentication, and as part of its banner serving system. Cookies may also be used with some fill-in forms, to retain default values between visits. 

  * **Registration Forms**

Forms exist on our site that require users to submit contact information (an email address). This information is used to send Netcraft articles and promotional information to interested visitors. Users may unsubscribe from receiving automated mail as a result of submitting this information. 

  * **Enquiry and Order Forms**

Our site use enquiry and order forms for customers to request details of, and purchase, services. We collect contact information (such as invoice and mail addresses) and financial information (a credit card number). This information is used for contacting customers and for billing. 

  * **External Links**

This site contains links to many other Web sites. Netcraft is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these sites. 

  * **Security**

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. 

  * **The Netcraft Anti-Phishing Extension**

The Extensions collect the following information. General: 

    * Hostnames visited (not URL paths) when browsing the web. These are used to identify phishing URLs on the site being visited that should be blocked, and to provide contextual reports and popularity ranking information. 
    * The Extension does not collect any other information. In particular, we do not collect personal information which can identify the browsing habits of individual users. 

Firefox specific: 

    * A unique identification reference is generated for each Extension installation. This is sent back to us when the Extension attempts to download updated versions of its software and is used for planning and licensing purposes. This is not sent as part of the Extension's normal operation when browsing the web. 
    * Very old versions of this Extension also collected MD5 hashes of URLs visited. 
  * **Use of Personal Information**

We process personal information collected through the web site and the Toolbar for the purposes of:  

    * Dealing with your enquiries, requests and reports of phishing URLs. 
    * Providing you with information about updates and enhancements to our products and services. 
    * Please contact us at [webmaster@netcraft.com](mailto:webmaster@netcraft.com) if, at any time, you do not wish to receive information about our products or services. 
  * **Disclosures**

We will not sell or disclose personal information to any third parties except successors in title to our business and, if required, government bodies and law enforcement agencies. 

  * **Access Rights**

You have a right to access the personal information held about you. To obtain a copy of the personal information we hold about you, please mail us at [webmaster@netcraft.com](mailto:webmaster@netcraft.com). 

  * **Contacting the Web Site**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, contact [webmaster@netcraft.com](mailto:webmaster@netcraft.com). 

#### Netcraft Services

##### Phishing & Fraud

##### Security Testing

##### Internet Data Mining

##### Internet Exploration

##### Performance

##### Advertising

#### About Netcraft

#### Article Categories

#### Archives
